You heard that already?
（大石(おおいし)）しかし耳が早いなぁ
（大石）私は悟史(さとし)君が犯人の
一点読みでしたからね
I was quite sure that
Satoshi-kun was the suspect.
（詩音(しおん)）聞かせてください
真犯人って一体何者です？
Please tell me.
Who exactly is the true suspect?
異常者とか聞きましたけど
I heard he's abnormal.
（大石）
実はねそいつ死んでるんですよ
To tell the truth,
the person was already dead...
県警からウチに
連絡があったときは既に…
...when the prefecture
police called us.
Dead?
死んでるって
どういうことですか？
What does that mean?
We're not sure if it was suicide
or if he became deranged...
県警の留置所の中でね
自殺か錯乱なのか―
そこんところがはっきりとは
分からないんですがねフッ…
...when he was held at
the prefecture police department.
Oh, right.
In Hinamizawa, it's being said...
（大石）
そうそう悟史君の失踪事件
...that he vanished because he
was spirited away by the demon.
雛見沢(ひなみざわ)じゃ鬼隠しに
遭ったなんていわれてるんだとか
オヤシロさまの
たたりってことでしょうかねえ？
Could they be referring
to Oyashiro-sama's curse?
That's ridiculous.
ばかばかしい！
- "Eye Opening" Chapter -
Episode 03: ONI'S BLOOD LINE
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
（詩音）１年目は
ダムの現場監督のバラバラ殺人
The first year was the dam
director's dismemberment.
The second year was the
accident with Satoshi's parents.
２年目は悟史君の両親の事故
The third year was the sudden
death of Furude Shrine's priest.
３年目は古手(ふるで)家の神主さんの突然死
All were Sonozaki...
みんな園崎(そのざき)家の…
Enemy
Uncooperative
Traitor
４年目の叔母は裏切り者の縁者か…
And the aunt from the fourth
year was a traitor's relative.
Oyashiro-sama's curse
オヤシロさまのたたりか…
Oyashiro-sama's curse, huh?
（鷹野(たかの)）ウフフフッ…
ごめんなさい
驚かせちゃったかしら？
I'm sorry.
Did I surprise you?
N-No.
い…いえ…
あなたが園崎詩音さん？
Are you Shion Sonozaki-san?
お姉の知り合いか何かですか？
Are you my sis's friend?
まあそんなところ　私鷹野三四(みよ)
Well, I guess you could say that.
I'm Miyo Takano.
“三四”って呼んでくれていいわよ
詩音ちゃん
You can call me Miyo.
Okay, Shion-chan?
あら怒ってるの？
Oh, are you mad?
That's too bad.
残念ね
私たち気が合うと思ったのに
I thought we'd get along well.
これは
その…私の妄想みたいなもので…
These are like
my wild imaginings.
（鷹野）オヤシロさまのたたりと
呼ばれる一連の連続怪死事件
The serial mysterious deaths
called Oyashiro-sama's curse.
いずれの事件も
個別に見えながら―
Though each seems
like a separate case...
確実に
１つの意思に基づいて行われている
...they're definitely being
done based on one intent.
毎年１人が
オヤシロさまのたたりに遭って死に
Every year, one person dies due
to Oyashiro-sama's curse...
１人が
いけにえにささげられて失踪する
...and another
disappears as a sacrifice.
ひ…１人がたたりで死んで
O-One dies due
to the curse, and another...
１人が何ですって？
What's that?
つまりね…
So the number of sacrifices
must match the number of deaths.
たたりで死んだ人数と同じだけ
いけにえも必要なの
いけにえ…
Sacrifice?
（鷹野）私が研究しているのは
古代雛見沢村の知られざる歴史
I'm researching the ancient,
unknown history of Hinamizawa.
暗黒史について
The dark history.
Before the Meiji Era, Hinamizawa
was called Onigafuchi Village.
（鷹野）鬼ヶ淵(おにがふち)村っていうのは
雛見沢村の明治(めいじ)以前の名前よ
You know a little about
the dark history, don't you?
暗黒史というのは
うすうすは知っているでしょう？
“人食い鬼の歴史”
（詩音）ああ人食い鬼の昔話
The history of
human-eating demons.
The old stories about
Then do you know the stories
about half-demon wizards...
（鷹野）では
その半人半鬼の仙人たちが―
時に山を下り―
...descending the mountain and
kidnapping humans to feast on?
人をさらって食らった宴(うたげ)の話は
知ってる？
えっ？何の話ですか？
W-What's that about?
彼らはね
犠牲者を拘束台に縛りつけ
It's said they strapped victims
down, and just like slicing a fish...
お魚をおろすときみたいに
はらわたを引きずり出して
...they dragged out the intestines
and drifted them down the river.
それを川に流したとされている
See, that's where the word
"Cotton Drifting" is derived from.
ほら
それが語源なの “綿流し”の
（詩音）ハッ…綿流しのお祭り…
The Cotton Drifting Festival.
These are the research notes.
I can show it to you as a treat.
これが研究ノートよ
特別に見せてあげてもいいわ
Oyashiro-sama's
sacrifice ritual...
オヤシロさまの
いけにえの儀式は―
犠牲者を
鬼ヶ淵の沼に沈めることなのよ
...is to drown the victim
in Onigafuchi Swamp.
Into that bottomless swamp.
あの底なし沼にね
じゃ
毎年のもう１人の犠牲者は―
Then you're saying the previous
years' victims are all in the swamp?
みんな 沼の底に沈んでいると？
まさか悟史君も？
Could Satoshi-kun also...
見てみる？
Want to look at it?
（詩音）葛西(かさい)なの？
（魅音(みおん)）私…
Kasai?
It's me.
（詩音）ど…どうぞお姉
C-Come in, Sis.
It seems like a quiet place.
（魅音）
落ち着いた雰囲気のとこだね
（魅音）生活はどう？
How's life?
まあ…新しい学校は
やっぱりつまらないよ
Well, the new school
is boring, as expected.
一応通ってはいるけど…
（魅音）アア…
I'm just attending, I guess.
あのさ…爪は治った？
Um, have your nails healed?
（詩音）もう
すっかり傷口は塞がったけど―
The wounds have closed...
でもまだだいぶゆがんでね…
あまり人には見せられないかな
...but they're still crooked.
I guess I can't really
show them to others.
I'm sorry.
ごめんね
You don't need to apologize.
謝らなくていいよ
次期当主の役割を演じただけ
You just enacted
the next head's duties.
（詩音）恨んじゃいないから
I don't hold a grudge.
ごめん
I'm sorry.
Okay. That forgave everything.
ＯＫ！
もうそれで全部チャラ！フフッ…
（魅音）本当に許してくれるの？
Will you really forgive me?
Even the thing with Satoshi?
悟史のことも…
（詩音）あっ…
I knew that you liked
Satoshi of course.
詩音が悟史のこと好きなのは
もちろん知ってたんだよ
あれだけ大勢の前で
熱愛宣言しちゃったからね
Well, I did admit it
in front of all those people.
でもばっちゃはあれで―
But Granny really thinks you
showed responsibility with that.
ホントに
けじめがついてると思ってるんだよ
If she didn't, that'd bother me...
そうでなきゃ困る
あれだけ痛い思いしたんだから
...since I went
through that much pain.
I wonder where Satoshi went.
悟史
どこに行っちゃったんだろうね？
Right then, the demon
awakened within me.
そのとき私の中に鬼が生まれた
S-Sorry.
ご…ごめん
悟史のことはホントに知らないの
I really don't know
anything about Satoshi.
（詩音）ウソだ
You're lying.
It's true.
Even Granny doesn't know.
ホント！ばっちゃだって
何も知らない　本当なの！
（詩音）ウソだ…ウソだウソだ！
You're lying!
You're lying! You're lying!
お前が悟史君を鬼隠ししたんだ！
You had Satoshi-kun
spirited away by the demon!
お前たち園崎家が！
お前たちが…お前たちが！
You, the Sonozaki family...
You guys! You guys!
返せ…私の悟史君を返せ！
Give him back.
Give me back my Satoshi-kun!
あっ…魅音これは…
Mion, these are...
（詩音）同じ傷…私と全く同じ
The same wounds...
Exactly the same as mine...
It's too heartbreaking to only
have your nails torn off.
詩音だけが爪を剥がされるなんて…
かわいそすぎるんだもん
（泣き声）
（魅音）なんで詩音ばっかり…
Why only you, when we're twins?
私たちは双子なのになんで…
Why?
私ね
ばっちゃにどなって言ったんだよ
I yelled at Granny to leave
you and Satoshi alone.
“悟史と詩音を
そっとしてあげてほしい”って
そしたらけじめをつけたら
見逃そうって話になって
Then she said if you showed
responsibility, she'd forgive you.
That's why you two
could've acted normally.
だからねもう
２人は普通にしててよかったんだよ
なのに…
なのに悟史がいなくなっちゃった
But...
But Satoshi disappeared...
（泣き声）
（魅音）信じて詩音…
Believe me, Shion!
本当にどうして
悟史がいなくなってしまったか―
I really don't know
why Satoshi disappeared.
分からないの
（詩音）魅音ごめん苦しかった？
Mion, I'm sorry.
Were you in pain?
詩音は
もっともっと苦しかったんだよね…
You were in
more pain, weren't you?
I told the demon inside
me that I believe Mion.
（詩音）私は私の中の鬼に告げた
“魅音を信じる”と
And at that time, I sealed away
my feelings for Satoshi-kun.
そして私はそのとき
悟史君への思いも封印した
心の奥深くへと…
Deep in my heart.
A year smoothly
passed by after that day.
それから１年は
何事もなく過ぎていった
Until that day...
あの日までは…
（ぶつかる音）
いたっ…ウウッ…
Ow.
もう！こんな所に止めてるの誰？
Jeez, who in
the world would park here?
Huh?
あれ？
デジャビュ？
Déjà vu?
Why you!
あっ…あのときと同じ
It's like that time...
（不良たち）ヘヘヘッ…こら
Come on...
いいかげんにしろよ！
（詩音）えっ？
That's enough!
（不良１）何だ？お前(めえ)は
What do you want?
ハッ…悟史君？
Satoshi-kun?
Stop showing off!
（不良２）
いい格好すんじゃねえよ！
（不良３）にいちゃんも
痛(いて)え目に遭いてえのか？ああ？
You want to get beat up too?
（不良１）おら！
Huh?
（圭一(けいいち)）アアッ！たんまたんま！
暴力はよくないぜハハッ…
Time out, time out.
Violence isn't good.
（不良２）うるせえ！
Shut up!
ああっ！おっとっと…
Whoa.
（不良２）ウワッ…アアッ！
Maebara-san, I called everyone!
（岡村(おかむら)）
前原(まえばら)さん みんな呼んできました！
（不良たち）チェッ…
くそやっべえ！ずらかれ！
Oh, shoot!
Go!
Are you all right, Mion?
半ベソかいてたのは
見なかったことにしてやるから―
I made sure not to see your
teary face, so cheer up, okay?
元気出せよなっ？
When They Cry
（詩音）お姉は圭ちゃんのこと
ホントに気に入ってるね
Sis, it seems like
you really like Kei-chan.
What would his
charm be in one word?
ズバリ圭ちゃんの魅力を
ひと言で示すとなに？
アハハハッ…そうだねえ…
Let's see...
やっぱり面白いとこかな？
I guess how funny he is.
（魅音）この間の部活は
街のおもちゃ屋でやったんだけどね
We did our last club activity
at the toy store, and...
I found out his name from Sis.
His name is Keiichi Maebara.
（詩音）お姉に聞いて分かった
彼の名前は前原圭一
He's one grade below me.
学年は１つ下
雛見沢に最近
引っ越してきたばかりだという
He recently moved
to Hinamizawa.
And Sis likes him.
そしてお姉のお気に入り
でねおじさんが
盛り上げてくれたからって―
And since Kei-chan helped fire
things up, he was given a doll.
圭ちゃんに
お人形をあげたんだよね
それが
もしかして欲しかったとか？
Are you saying you wanted it?
But Kei-chan didn't give it to me.
（魅音）
でも圭ちゃんはくれなかった
“魅音には似合わないよな”って
He said it didn't suit me.
（泣き声）
レナにあげちゃって…
He gave it to Rena.
I want to start over.
やり直したい
圭ちゃんに初めて会ったときから
やり直して―
I want to start over
from the day we met...
...and make sure
he thinks of me as a girl.
今度はちゃんと
女の子だと思ってもらえるように…
Sis, you're being too serious.
You can still make up for it.
お姉深刻すぎ
今からでも修正可能だって
It's not like there's a problem.
トラブってるわけでもないんだし
（魅音）うん…
変に構えないでふだんどおり
さりげにアピール！
Don't act differently, be normal,
and try to attract him naturally.
あとレナって子には
クギを刺しておくこと
Also, make sure
that Rena knows.
ウウッ…
確かにレナはかわいいからなぁ
Rena definitely is cute.
ライバルがいるなら
うかうかできないよお姉
If there's a rival,
you can't be slacking off.
Sis, tears have
the power to attract guys...
涙は男を引き寄せる力はあるけど
つなぎ止めておく力はないからね
...but they can't keep them.
Keep smiling...
ふだんは笑ってて…
...and cry at certain points.
ポイントで泣く！
う～ん…
萌(も)えの典型パターンのひとつかも
Sounds like a typical
supergirly style.
私も圭ちゃんで実践してみるかな
Should I test it with Kei-chan too?
えっ？ダ…ダメだよダメ！
N-N-No, no!
Then do you want to race
to see who wins his heart first?
なんならお姉どっちが
圭ちゃんの気を引けるか競争する？
ヤダヤダ絶対ヤダ！
詩音雛見沢に来たら追い返す！
No, no, never!
Shion, I'll turn you
away if you go there!
I'm glad, Sis.
良かったじゃんお姉
好きな男の子のことで
悩めるなんて羨ましい
I envy you for being able
to worry about a guy you like.
私なんかいないんだよ…
I don't have a person like that.
えっ？
（詩音）ううん何でもない
It's nothing.
お姉と圭ちゃんが
楽しく過ごしていても―
Even if they have a good time
together, no one will blame them.
誰も とがめない
羨ましいなんて思わない
妬んだりなんかしない
I won't be envious.
I won't be jealous.
私がとがめられたから―
Just because I was blamed
doesn't mean I want her to be.
同じように
とがめられてほしいなんて…
悟史君がいなくなってから
１年がたってしまう
It'll be one year
since Satoshi disappeared.
The Cotton Drifting
Festival will come again.
またあの綿流しのお祭りが
やって来る
And on that day, when Kei-chan,
who thought I was Mion...
そしてその当日私を勝手に
魅音だと思い込んだ圭ちゃんが―
私と腕を組んで歩いていたところに
お姉とばったり…
...was walking with me,
we suddenly ran into Sis.
それで
こんな騒ぎになってしまった
And that's how this mess started.
（沙都子(さとこ)）まったく圭一さんの
ドスケベぶりにはあきれましてよ
I am sick of how
perverted Keiichi-san is.
（梨花(りか)）
男の子ならしかたないのですよ
You can't help it since he's a boy.
（ﾚﾅ）魅ぃちゃんも詩ぃちゃんも
圭一君困ってるよ
Mi-chan and Shi-chan,
Keiichi-kun's troubled by this.
お姉このまま―
Sis, do you want to keep playing
tug of war until Kei-chan tears?
圭ちゃんが引きちぎれるまで
引っ張りっこする？
詩音が引っ張らなければ
済むことでしょう
This'll end if you stop pulling.
詩音はさっさと興宮(おきのみや)へ帰れ！
Go back to Okinomiya already!
Okay.
はい
（魅音･圭一）アアッ！
Sure, I'll do that.
了解そうするね！
（圭一）痛え…
（詩音）じゃ圭ちゃん
Well, Kei-chan...
...Sis might bite me if I tease her
any more, so I'll go home now.
これ以上からかうと
お姉にかみつかれかねないので
今日はこれで帰りま～す
（圭一）あっ詩音
Hey, Shion.
そのさ…今日はありがとうな
Um, thanks for today.
あああんなのお安いご用です
Oh, that was nothing.
Then see you later, Shion.
じゃまたな詩音
（詩音）ハッ…
（詩音）
アハハハッ…じゃまたねお姉！
See you later, Sis!
二度と来るなー！
Never come back!
Rena, you guard! Satoko,
set traps! Rika-chan, throw salt!
レナは警戒沙都子はトラップ
梨花ちゃんは塩まいて！
ハァハァ… ハァ…
ごめん悟史君…ごめんごめん
I'm sorry, Satoshi-kun.
Sorry. Sorry.
私は悟史君のことを
忘れていないんだよ
I haven't forgotten about you.
ちゃんと覚えてるんだよ
I remember you clearly.
悟史君のいない生活なんて―
Life without you is just
gray, lonely, and boring.
灰色で寂しくて
つまんないだけなんだよ
Then see you later, Shion.
全然温(あった)かくなんかなかったよ
うれしくなんかなかった
It wasn't warm at all.
I wasn't happy.
I hate those who
are so insensitive.
あんなデリカシーのないヤツ
嫌いだよ！
（泣き声）
悟史君…
Satoshi-kun...
悟史君…悟史君
悟史君ーっ！
（泣き声）
Satoshi-kun!
Where are you? Where?
どこにいるの？どこに…
Satoshi-kun?
悟史君？
So you were there.
そこにいたんだ！
ウッ…すいません
- Excuse me.
- Oh, Shion-chan.
（鷹野）あら詩音ちゃん
（詩音）うん？
T-Takano-san!
（詩音）た… 鷹野さん！
（富竹(とみたけ)）挨拶をするのは
これが初めてだね　僕は富竹
This is the first time
we've met, right?
I'm Tomitake.
魅音ちゃんの
双子の妹だって話は聞いてるよ
I heard that you're
Mion-chan's twin sister.
Nice to meet you.
よろしくね
富竹さんこそ
スゴ腕のカメラマンだとか
I've also heard you're
a skilled photographer.
One who sucks
and can't sell much.
大して売れてない下手くそだけどね
ハハハハッ…
You haven't come to
the library since that day.
（鷹野）
あれから図書館には来ないのね
研究の同志としてもっと
いろいろお話ししたかったのに
As a fellow researcher, I wanted
to discuss many more things.
Let's say that I'll go if I feel like it.
気が向いたら
まあそのうちってことで
I guess I should get going now.
そろそろ私も行くかな
You're going to watch
Rika's dance too, aren't you?
鷹野さんたちも
見に行くんですよね？
梨花ちゃまの踊り
実はねこれから
祭具殿の中に入ってみようと思うの
To tell the truth, we're thinking
of going into the ritual tool shrine.
でもあそこには南京錠が
かかってて立ち入り禁止じゃ…
But there's a padlock on it,
and it's off-limits.
Jiro-san is good at many things.
（鷹野）ジロウさん
とってもうまいのよいろいろと
If you don't mind,
you should sneak by later.
（鷹野）良かったら
あとでこっそりいらっしゃいな
This chance will
never come again.
二度とないチャンスよ
The ritual tool shrine...
Lots of torture tools.
祭具殿か…拷問道具がいっぱい…
あっ…悟史君の鬼隠しのことも
そこに入れば何か分かるのかな？
I might find out how Satoshi
was spirited away if I go there.
（詩音）１人じゃ怖いけど
圭ちゃんが一緒なら…
It's scary if I go alone,
but if Kei-chan's with me...
Even if we're caught,
Mion will forgive us for sure.
もし見つかっても今度は
魅音もきっと見逃してくれる
奉納演舞がよく見えるとこって
まだ遠いのか？
Is the place with a better view of
the offering dance much further?
えっ？
そんなこと誰が言いました？
Who said that?
Tomitake-san.
（詩音）富竹さん
（鷹野･富竹）あっ…
That's the guardian god
of Hinamizawa, Oyashiro-sama.
（鷹野）あれが
雛見沢の守り神オヤシロさまよ
オヤシロさまめ…
Oyashiro-sama...
もしもお前が悟史君を
消した張本人なら許さない
If you're the one who erased
Satoshi-kun, I'll never forgive you.
Never.
許さない…絶対に許さない！
I will never forgive you.
What Takano-san said was true.
鷹野さんの言っていたことは
本当だった
この村には残酷な風習が
ずっとずっと息づいていたんだ
In this village, the brutal
custom has been continued.
（物音）
悟史君？悟史君なの？
Satoshi-kun?
Is that you, Satoshi-kun?
ねえ悟史君だよね？
You are Satoshi-kun, aren't you?
It's not Satoshi-kun.
悟史君じゃない！
ワアッ！どうしたんだよ？詩音
ひょっとして怖くなったか？
What's wrong, Shion?
Did you get scared?
It's tonight that Oyashiro-sama's
curse will occur, isn't it?
そういえば今夜よね
オヤシロさまのたたりがある夜は
（物音）
これが聞こえてないの？
Don't they hear this?
They're about to finish.
そろそろ終わりそうだよ
Sonozaki
（男性）ホント長居しちゃって
じゃばっちゃん帰るよ
ウ～ン…
There's no helping it.
（お魎(りょう)）しゃあもねえやんな
あんの若いのんも
ちょい出張り過ぎやったんや
That youngster was too nosy.
Yes. We can't help it because
she angered Oyashiro-sama.
（魅音）まあね
オヤシロさまのお怒りに
触れたんだからしかたないしね
The police are investigating it,
but are you sure about that?
（お魎）警察は調べとるんが
すったらん間違いなかんね？
It's probably Takano-san.
多分ね鷹野さんだろうね
"Angered Oyashiro-sama"...
“オヤシロさまの
お怒りに触れた”？
"The police are investigating"...
“警察が調べている”？
“多分鷹野さん”？
"It's probably Takano-san"...
そして今日という日の意味
And the meaning of today.
Oyashiro-sama's curse
happened for the fifth time!
５年目も起こったんだ
オヤシロさまのたたりが！
Why are they saying Takano-san
angered Oyashiro-sama?
どうして魅音と鬼ばばは―
鷹野さんがオヤシロさまの
お怒りに触れたなんて言ってるの？
祭具殿に忍び込んだことが
バレてる！
They found out we snuck
into the ritual shrine...
（ﾚﾅ）魅ぃちゃんにはない？
Have you ever experienced it?
ひたひたと
ずっと足音がついてきて
The footsteps follow you...
...and it stands over your pillow
and looks down at you at night.
夜は枕元にまで立たれて
見下ろされてる経験
Someone is observing
you from far away.
誰かが遠くから
じっとうかがってる
Someone is always following.
誰かがずっとつけてくる
悟史君が経験していることは―
The experiences
he's going through...
...all foreshadows
Oyashiro-sama's curse.
全て
オヤシロさまのたたりの前触れなの
Then what's that?
じゃなに？
祭具殿に忍び込んだときから―
From the time I snuck
into the ritual shrine...
...the thing that's been
stalking me all along is...
私の後ろを
ベタベタと付きまとっているの？
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What you seek is slight comfort.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）求めるのは僅かな安らぎ
見えるのは憎しみの回廊
What you can see
is a gallery of hatred.
落ちたのは暗闇の向こう
Where you fell
is beyond the darkness.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
When They Cry.
"Eye Opening" Chapter,
Episode 4: REVENGE.
- "Eye Opening" Chapter -
Episode 04: REVENGE
"Eye Opening" Chapter,
Episode 4: REVENGE.
あなたは信じられますか？
- "Eye Opening" Chapter -
Episode 04: REVENGE
Can you believe it?